Hello English learners, welcome to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎来到EnglishPod。
My name is Marto.
我叫马托。
And my name is Catherine.
我叫凯瑟琳。
And today we're talking about something very, very important in the computer age.
今天我们要讨论的是计算机时代中一件非常重要的事情。
Internet.
互联网。
Internet and internet connections.
互联网和互联网连接。
Right.
好的。
I think, well, so many people use the internet now and have it, but it's sometimes a little
我想，嗯，现在很多人都在用互联网，也都有网络，但有时候还是有点
bit complicated to maybe get a plan or maybe if you're not too familiar with the terms,
有点复杂，可能不太容易制定计划，或者如果你对这些术语不太熟悉的话。
that's what we're going to be looking at today.
这就是我们今天要探讨的内容。
So listen out for some of these words today.
所以今天留意听这些词。
We're talking on the phone with someone who's going to help us get a plan.
我们正在和一位能帮我们制定计划的人通电话。
When we come back, we'll be talking all about what some of these words and phrases mean.
我们回来后会详细讨论这些单词和短语的含义。
So if you're confused, just wait a couple seconds and we'll be back.
所以如果你感到困惑，稍等几秒钟，我们马上回来。
Welcome to Gallinet.
欢迎来到加里内特。
How can I help you?
我能帮你什么吗？
Hi, I would like to get an internet plan for my house.
你好，我想为我家办一个网络套餐。
Of course.
当然。
We have three different plans with different prices you can choose from.
我们有三种不同价位的套餐供您选择。
The first one is the cheapest, but most basic plan, which is $30 a month.
第一个是最便宜的，但也是最基础的套餐，每月30美元。
This is for broadband internet with a download speed of 512 kbps.
这是用于宽带互联网的，下载速度为512 kbps。
I have no idea what kbps means.
我完全不知道 kbps 是什么意思。
I just want to be able to get online, play games and chat with my friends.
我只想能上网、玩游戏、和朋友聊天。
Oh, and watch movies online as well.
哦，还有在线看电影。
Well, this connection might be a bit too slow for your needs.
嗯，这个连接速度可能对你来说有点太慢了。
I suggest you get the premium package for $50 a month, which includes a connection speed
我建议你选每月50美元的高级套餐，包含连接速度。
of 2 megabytes.
2兆字节。
That way, you can play games online without any lag.
这样，你就可以在线玩游戏而不会卡顿了。
This package also includes a wireless router and a personal firewall, absolutely free.
这个套餐还包括一个无线路由器和个人防火墙，完全免费。
Do I have to pay an installation fee?
我必须付安装费吗？
Lucky for you, this month we aren't charging our normal installation fee.
算你走运，这个月我们免收常规安装费。
You're saving yourself $100 right there.
你这就省了100美元。
And we'll throw in this pen drive.
我们还会附赠这个U盘。
Awesome!
太棒了！
All right, so interesting.
好的，真有意思。
A lot of these are technical terms specifically for internet and computers and connection
很多这些术语都是专门针对互联网、电脑和连接的技术词汇。
and all that stuff.
以及所有那些东西。
Yeah, and the nice thing about some of these words is that they can be used in other ways
是的，而且这些词的好处之一是它们还能用在其他场合。
as well.
也一样。
So, we're learning about these and expanding our vocabularies, but they're useful in many
所以，我们正在学习这些词汇并扩展我们的词汇量，但它们在很多方面都很有用。
other contexts as well.
以及其他语境。
Okay, so let's get started with these words now in Language Takeaway.
好的，那我们现在就从“语言要点”部分开始学习这些词。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
So this first phrase, for example, is something that you see advertised all the time and it's
所以第一个短语，比如说，是一种你经常看到广告的东西，它是一种
a kind of internet connection.
互联网连接方式。
Broadband internet.
宽带互联网。
Okay, so internet is pretty clear, but broadband, you might be asking, what the heck can this
好的，“互联网”这个词很清楚，但“宽带”你可能要问，这到底是什么意思？
mean?
什么意思？
Okay, so you have broad.
好的，所以有“宽”。
So broad means wide.
“宽”就是宽阔的意思。
And a band is basically a frequency at which something works.
“带”基本上是指某种东西工作的频率。
Like bandwidth.
比如“带宽”。
Bandwidth, uh-huh.
带宽，嗯哼。
So you have broadband, you have fast or high speed internet.
所以你有宽带，也就是快速或高速互联网。
That means the bigger the space is, the more information can be transferred.
这意味着空间越大，能传输的信息就越多。
So it's a fast connection essentially.
所以本质上它是一种快速的连接。
Exactly.
没错。
Before broadband, we had dial-up internet.
在宽带之前，我们有拨号上网。
Ooh.
哦。
Do-do-do-do-do-do-do-do.
嘟-嘟-嘟-嘟-嘟-嘟-嘟-嘟。
Yeah.
是啊。
Do-do-do-do-do-do-do-do.
嘟-嘟-嘟-嘟-嘟-嘟-嘟-嘟。
Remember AOL?
还记得美国在线吗？
Yeah, exactly.
是啊，没错。
It was so slow.
它太慢了。
So you had to use your modem and call a number and then get connected by telephone.
所以你得用调制解调器，拨一个号码，然后通过电话连接。
So it was a dial-up connection, but it was so slow.
所以那是拨号连接，但太慢了。
And every time it broke, the connection would break.
而且每次断线，连接就会中断。
You had to dial-up again and go through the whole process.
你得重新拨号，再走一遍整个过程。
It was so annoying.
太烦人了。
Exactly.
没错。
So fortunately now, not many people use dial-up anymore and we have broadband internet.
所以幸运的是，现在没多少人再用拨号了，我们有宽带互联网。
Now if you have broadband internet, it's really convenient because you can download any type
如果你有宽带互联网，真的很方便，因为你可以下载任何类型的
of application or music, videos, et cetera.
应用程序、音乐、视频等等。
Right.
对。
So this is another key computer word that actually has a couple of different uses.
所以这是另一个关键的电脑词汇，实际上有几种不同的用法。
For example, as you said, you can download music or download photos.
比如，就像你说的，你可以下载音乐或下载照片。
That means you find a photo on the internet that you like and you could save it on your
这意味着你在网上找到一张喜欢的照片，可以把它保存到你的
computer.
电脑上。
But you can also have a download.
但你也可以有“下载”这个名词。
So it can be a thing too.
所以它也可以是一样东西。
Okay.
好的。
So if maybe you're downloading three different files, you have three downloads.
所以如果你在下载三个不同的文件，你就有三个下载任务。
Okay.
好的。
So to download and download.
所以就是下载和下载。
Very good.
很好。
So now with internet, you have different speeds as we talked about, right?
那么现在有了互联网，就像我们之前聊的，有不同的速度，对吧？
How fast you're downloading something.
你下载东西的速度有多快。
And the guy mentioned 512 kbps.
那个人提到了512 kbps。
Oh no.
哦不。
Not another one of these kbps.
又来了一个kbps。
So this one, actually this was pretty simple.
这个其实挺简单的。
You can think about kilobytes.
你可以想想千字节。
You've heard about megabytes, kilobytes.
你听说过兆字节、千字节。
This is a size.
这是一个大小单位。
How fast you can receive these packets of information.
你接收这些信息包的速度有多快。
So 512 kilobytes per second.
所以是每秒512千字节。
Per second, that's, I have no idea how much that is.
每秒，那……我不知道那是多少。
It's maybe a lot.
可能挺多的。
It sounds like a lot.
听起来挺多的。
Right.
对。
Well, basically it is a lot, but we saw later that he was asking for a connection speed
嗯，基本上确实挺多的，但我们后来看到他要求的是连接速度
of two megabytes.
两兆字节。
Oh, so mega is bigger than kpbs, right?
哦，所以兆比kbps大，对吧？
Right.
对。
All right.
好的。
So these are different speeds of transferring information, right?
所以这些是传输信息的不同速度，对吧？
So this is a way for you to see what kind of internet plan you want.
所以这是让你了解自己想要哪种网络套餐的方式。
Exactly.
没错。
And so we have kilobytes, we have megabytes, and basically you want a faster connection
所以我们有千字节、兆字节，基本上你想要更快的连接
speed because you want to avoid lag.
速度，因为你想避免延迟。
Ooh, lag.
哦，延迟。
All right.
好的。
This is a word that you can use in a lot of different ways.
这个词可以用在很多不同的地方。
For example, my brother always lags behind.
比如，我哥哥总是落后。
Okay.
好的。
So it's a verb, but in this case we're talking about the noun.
所以它是动词，但在这里我们说的是名词。
So lag is slowness.
所以延迟就是缓慢。
Yeah.
是的。
It's like a delay.
就像一种延迟。
Yeah.
是啊。
It's a delay in something.
就是某件事有延迟。
So in this case, I can't even play my video games because there's too much lag.
所以在这种情况下，我连游戏都玩不了，因为延迟太高了。
So that means the internet's too slow.
那意味着网速太慢了。
Too slow.
太慢了。
Exactly.
没错。
So that's what happens when you have a slow connection speed, you have lag.
所以这就是连接速度慢时会发生的情况，你会遇到延迟。
And as you can say, it refers to something that's slow or delayed.
正如你所说，它指的是某件事缓慢或延迟。
So you can use it in other contexts when you want to say something is a little bit slow.
所以当你想说某件事有点慢时，可以在其他语境中使用它。
Well and another key thing here as we're talking about internet connections is the router.
嗯，另一个关键点是，当我们谈论互联网连接时，就是路由器。
So router is something that helps us to route an internet connection.
路由器是帮助我们路由互联网连接的东西。
So for example.
比如说。
So it basically distributes the internet connection to different computers or to different users.
它基本上将互联网连接分配给不同的电脑或不同的用户。
And some of these you plug in and some of them are wireless.
有些需要插线，有些是无线的。
That means without a wire.
意思是没有电线。
So a wireless router is something, a little box in your house that allows you to maybe
所以无线路由器就是你家里的一个小盒子，可以让你
have three or four computers on one broadband connection.
在一个宽带连接上使用三四台电脑。
Right.
对。
So it's very popular now.
现在很流行。
You go to Starbucks and you have Wi-Fi.
你去星巴克就有Wi-Fi。
In order to have Wi-Fi or wireless internet, you need a router, a wireless router.
要使用Wi-Fi或无线网络，你需要一个路由器，一个无线路由器。
Okay.
好的。
So wireless router.
所以是无线路由器。
And finally, what is something that might get in the way of a connection?
最后，什么东西可能会妨碍连接？
You have a firewall.
你有防火墙。
Very important security measure when navigating the internet.
上网时非常重要的安全措施。
All right.
好的。
So personal firewall is a firewall that you have on your computer to keep people from
个人防火墙就是你电脑上的一种防火墙，用来防止别人
spying on you.
监视你。
This keeps other people out.
它把其他人挡在外面。
So it's exactly that.
就是这样。
It's a wall between your computer and the outside world.
它是你电脑和外部世界之间的一堵墙。
So it protects you from any type of maybe malicious intruders.
所以它能保护你免受任何可能的恶意入侵者的侵害。
Right.
对。
And oftentimes governments and public offices, things like that, law offices, they have firewalls
而且通常政府、公共办公室、律师事务所之类的地方，他们都有防火墙
to protect the information that they store because it's so important that it's secretive.
来保护他们存储的信息，因为这些信息的保密性非常重要。
Yeah.
是啊。
So firewalls.
所以是防火墙。
There are many different types of firewalls, but a personal firewall is just a basic one.
防火墙有很多不同类型，但个人防火墙只是基本的一种。
Great.
太好了。
So that is our language takeaway for today.
这就是我们今天要学的语言点。
Let's check out this dialogue again and slow it down a bit this time.
让我们再看一遍这段对话，这次放慢速度。
Welcome to Gallinet.
欢迎来到Gallinet。
How can I help you?
有什么可以帮您的？
Hi.
你好。
I would like to get an internet plan for my house.
我想为我家办一个网络套餐。
Of course.
当然可以。
We have three different plans with different prices you can choose from.
我们有三种不同价格的套餐供您选择。
The first one is the cheapest, but most basic plan, which is $30 a month.
第一种是最便宜但最基础的套餐，每月30美元。
This is for broadband internet with a download speed of 512 kbps.
这是宽带网络，下载速度为512 kbps。
I have no idea what kbps means.
我完全不知道kbps是什么意思。
I just want to be able to get online, play games, and chat with my friends.
我只想能上网、玩游戏、和朋友聊天。
Oh, and watch movies online as well.
哦，还有在线看电影。
Well, this connection might be a bit too slow for your needs.
嗯，这个连接速度可能对您的需求来说有点慢。
I suggest you get the premium package for $50 a month, which includes a connection speed
我建议您选择每月50美元的高级套餐，其中包括连接速度
of 2 megabytes.
为2兆。
That way, you can play games online without any lag.
这样，您就可以在线玩游戏而不会卡顿。
This package also includes a wireless router and a personal firewall, absolutely free.
这个套餐还免费包含一个无线路由器和个人防火墙。
Do I have to pay an installation fee?
我需要支付安装费吗？
Lucky for you, this month we aren't charging our normal installation fee.
您很幸运，这个月我们免收常规安装费。
You're saving yourself $100 right there, and we'll throw in this pen drive.
您直接省了100美元，而且我们还会赠送这个U盘。
Awesome.
太棒了。
All right, great.
好的，很好。
So we just heard all these words that we looked at before, but now why don't we take a look
我们刚才听到了之前学过的所有单词，但现在我们来看看
at some of these phrases in Fluency Builder.
流畅表达中的一些短语。
Fluency Builder.
流畅表达。
What's this first one?
第一个是什么？
I can't read it.
我看不清。
I have no idea.
我不知道。
What?
什么？
Well, didn't you write it down?
嗯，你没写下来吗？
I have no idea what you're talking about.
我完全不知道你在说什么。
All right.
好吧。
Enough games.
别闹了。
No.
不。
I have no idea.
我不知道。
Well, it's going to treat this as a phrase that gets said as is.
嗯，我们会把它当作一个固定短语来对待。
We're not going to take bits and pieces of it.
我们不会拆开它。
So I have no idea, or he has no idea, is a way to say, listen.
所以“我不知道”或“他不知道”是一种表达方式，意思是听着，
I don't know.
我不知道。
I really don't know.
我真的不知道。
Right.
对。
The guy was talking about KBPS and all these things, and the other guy was like, I have
那个人在说什么KBPS之类的东西，另一个人就说，我完全
no idea what you're talking about.
不知道你在说什么。
I don't understand.
我不明白。
And I can definitely empathize.
我完全能理解那种感觉。
You can relate.
你能感同身受。
Yeah.
是啊。
Well, we'll leave that for another one.
好吧，我们下次再聊那个。
But after this, we've got bucks.
但在这之后，我们提到了“bucks”。
So bucks.
所以是“bucks”。
Is this slang?
这是俚语吗？
Bucks.
“Bucks”。
A hundred bucks.
一百块。
Two hundred bucks.
两百块。
A lot of money.
很多钱。
Right.
对。
So bucks is basically another way of saying dollars.
所以“bucks”基本上就是“dollars”的另一种说法。
All right.
好的。
So this is a way for...
所以这是一种……
Well, this is a way that most Americans talk about money.
嗯，这是大多数美国人谈论钱的方式。
It's one buck is one US dollar.
一“buck”就是一美元。
All right.
好的。
So can I borrow 10 bucks, Marco?
那我能借十块钱吗，Marco？
Right.
对。
Yeah, sure.
嗯，当然。
There you go.
给你。
Now, bucks, you can only use it for American currency, right?
那么，“bucks”只能用于美国货币，对吧？
You can't use it for like euros or...
你不能用它来说欧元之类的……
No.
不能。
I mean, I wouldn't say like 10 euros would be 10 bucks.
我的意思是，我不会说十欧元是十“bucks”。
No, no, no, no.
不不不不。
Usually, you say this about American dollars and you say this just when you're hanging
通常，你只在闲聊时用这个词说美元，或者问这个多少钱？
out or how much does this cost?
哦，五块钱。
Oh, five bucks.
Yeah.
是啊。
Very good.
很好。
So the guy was telling him about the price of the internet and everything.
所以那个人在告诉他网络的价格之类的。
And he said that he's going to throw in a pen drive, right?
他还说会送一个U盘，对吧？
He's going to throw it?
他要扔出去吗？
He's going to throw it at him.
他要朝他扔过去。
No, he's going to throw in a pen drive for free.
不，他要免费附送一个U盘。
Oh, sweet.
哦，不错。
So throw in means to add.
所以“throw in”意思是额外添加。
Or include.
或者包含在内。
Include.
包含。
So, listen.
那么，听着。
Sir, here's your large popcorn and I'm going to throw in a small diet Coke for free.
先生，这是您的大份爆米花，我再免费送您一小杯健怡可乐。
Wow.
哇。
How generous of me.
我真是大方啊。
So you throw in something, you include it for free, right?
所以“throw in something”就是免费包含某样东西，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
So this is usually a complimentary item.
所以这通常是一种赠品。
Great.
太好了。
I think this word is really interesting or this phrase.
我觉得这个词或这个短语真的很有趣。
So why don't we listen to a couple of other examples using throw in.
那我们不如再听几个使用“throw in”的例子吧。
Example one.
例子一。
If you buy two pizzas, we will throw in another one for free.
如果你买两个披萨，我们会免费再送一个。
Example two.
例子二。
Tell you what.
我跟你说。
I'll buy this computer if you throw in a pair of headphones.
如果你附送一副耳机，我就买这台电脑。
Deal?
成交？
Example three.
例子三。
The salesman threw in a subscription to the local newspaper for buying his product.
销售员因为顾客买了他的产品，免费附送了一份当地报纸的订阅。
Isn't that great?
是不是很棒？
All right.
好了。
Great.
太好了。
So good examples.
很好的例子。
I think it's clear now.
我想现在清楚了。
The phrases, all these words related to the internet.
这些短语，所有跟互联网相关的词。
Absolutely.
当然。
And so useful.
而且非常有用。
Right.
对。
So why don't we listen to this dialogue for the last time and then we'll come back and
那我们最后再听一遍这段对话，然后回来
talk a little bit more.
再聊一会儿。
Welcome to Gallinet.
欢迎来到Gallinet。
How can I help you?
有什么可以帮您的？
Hi.
你好。
I would like to get an internet plan for my house.
我想为我家办一个网络套餐。
Of course.
当然。
We have three different plans with different prices you can choose from.
我们有三种不同的套餐，价格各异，你可以选择。
The first one is the cheapest but most basic plan, which is $30 a month.
第一种是最便宜但最基础的套餐，每月30美元。
This is for broadband internet with a download speed of 512 kbps.
这是宽带互联网，下载速度为512 kbps。
I have no idea what kbps means.
我不知道kbps是什么意思。
I just want to be able to get online, play games, and chat with my friends.
我只想能上网、玩游戏、和朋友聊天。
Oh, and watch movies online as well.
哦，还有在线看电影。
Well, this connection might be a bit too slow for your needs.
嗯，这个连接速度对你的需求来说可能有点慢。
I suggest you get the premium package for $50 a month, which includes a connection speed
我建议你选择高级套餐，每月50美元，包括连接速度
of 2 megabytes.
为2兆字节。
That way, you can play games online without any lag.
这样，你就可以无延迟地在线玩游戏了。
This package also includes a wireless router and a personal firewall, absolutely free.
这个套餐还包括一个无线路由器和个人防火墙，完全免费。
Do I have to pay an installation fee?
我需要支付安装费吗？
Lucky for you, this month we aren't charging our normal installation fee.
你运气好，这个月我们不收取正常的安装费。
You are saving yourself $100 right there.
你这就省了100美元。
And we'll throw in this pen drive.
我们还会赠送这个U盘。
Awesome!
太棒了！
So the internet is a big deal nowadays and now you can do so much on it.
所以现在互联网是个大事，你可以在上面做很多事情。
Not only navigate websites anymore, but watch movies, download applications, photos, Facebook,
不仅仅是浏览网站，还可以看电影、下载应用程序、照片、Facebook，
all this type of things now you can do on the internet.
所有这些事情现在都可以在互联网上做。
You can even do it from your phone, like when you're in the bathroom or on the train.
你甚至可以在手机上做，比如在浴室或火车上。
I mean, it's scary.
我是说，这有点吓人。
We're always connected.
我们总是连接着。
Right.
对。
So it's interesting.
所以挺有意思的。
You're always connected.
你总是连接着。
You're always online with people.
你总是和人们在线。
And it's actually very noticeable when you maybe live somewhere else.
而且当你住在别的地方时，这种感觉特别明显。
Before you used to have to write letters.
以前你得写信。
I don't think many people receive handwritten letters anymore.
我觉得现在很少有人收到手写信了。
Never.
从来没有。
I'm speaking for myself.
我说的是我自己。
I never receive.
我从来没收到过。
And I don't write them either.
我也不写。
So I guess I'm guilty of it.
所以我想我也有责任。
So now people just send emails.
所以现在人们只发电子邮件。
Obviously it's more convenient, but maybe it's a little bit less significant maybe than
显然这更方便，但可能比
actually going to the post office or taking the time to write a letter, going to the post
实际去邮局或花时间写信、去邮局
office and stuff.
之类的事情少了一些意义。
Well, I don't know.
嗯，我不知道。
I mean, there's something nice about having a physical thing you can hold on to, but I
我的意思是，能拥有一件可以握在手里的实体物品确实不错，但我
wonder if one day we're going to forget how to write.
想知道有一天我们会不会忘记怎么写字。
You know, like write with a pen.
你知道，就是用笔写字。
With a pen and pencil.
用钢笔和铅笔。
Exactly.
没错。
We're going to have these little PDAs and these little iPhones and they're going to
我们会有这些小型的PDA和这些小iPhone，它们会
just, you're going to talk and they're going to take everything down in note form for you.
直接，你说话，它们就会帮你把所有内容记成笔记形式。
Well, now it's kind of happening with the Kindle, right?
嗯，现在Kindle不就在做类似的事吗？
Now you can have books on this electronic device that lets you read through them.
现在你可以把书放在这个电子设备上，通过它来阅读。
You can carry a hundred books with you to the beach.
你可以带着一百本书去海滩。
So now you don't even really need physical books, which is good on some level because
所以现在你甚至不需要实体书了，这在某种程度上是好事，因为
you know, you're saving trees and space and all that stuff.
你知道，你在节省树木、空间之类的东西。
But there's something physical about reading a book.
但读书也有一种实体感。
You hold it, you flip the pages, you know how many pages you have left.
你拿着它，翻页，知道还剩多少页。
I don't know.
我不知道。
We'll see.
我们走着瞧吧。
Maybe I'll be a convert one day, but for now I'm good with paper books.
也许有一天我会被说服，但现在我还是喜欢纸质书。
All right.
好吧。
So what do you guys think about the internet, about electronic books?
那么，你们对互联网、对电子书怎么看？
You can also tell us any problems or confusion you have with the things that we talked about
你也可以告诉我们，关于我们今天讨论的内容，你有什么问题或困惑
today.
今天。
Hopefully everything is clear, but if not, we are here to answer your questions.
希望一切都清楚，但如果不清楚，我们在这里回答你的问题。
We like to do so.
我们很乐意这样做。
So check out our website, EnglishPod.com.
所以请访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
All right.
好吧。
We'll see you guys there and until next time.
我们会在那里见你们，下次再见。
Goodbye everyone.
大家再见。